Lefteris Kampianakis, Ph.D.

60 N. McClintock Drive, Suite 1 - 85226, Chandler, AZ - USA

Objective

I have 9+ years of experience in designing, integrating, fabricating, and testing hardware for wireless sensing devices and networks. Specifically, I have focused on ultra low-power, ultra high data-rate backscatter wireless communication systems and sensors.

I'm currently working as an Senior Applications Engineer with the Integrated Circuits department of Cirtec Medical.

Technical Interests and Expertise

- o System-level design and integration of industrial products
- \circ μ Power consumption & high data-rate embedded systems
- Integrated high bandwidth brain-computer interfaces (BCI)
- o High data-rate software-defined radio receivers
- Multilayer circuit/board design for RF and sensing applications

Education

University of Washington, Electrical Engineering

Ph.D., Thesis: "High data-rate low-power wireless communication systems for brain computer interfaces"

(March 2019)

Seattle, WA, USA

Advisor: Prof. Matthew Reynolds

Technical University of Crete, Electronic & Computer Engineering

M.Sc., Thesis: "Scatter radio sensor network with analog frequency modulation principles"

Chania, Greece July 2014

Advisor: Prof. Aggelos Bletsas

Diploma of Eng. (5 year program), Thesis: "Custom over the air programmable embedded radios"

December 2011

Advisor: Prof. Aggelos Bletsas

Selected Work Experience

More information and multimedia available at http://staff.washington.edu/ekampian/projects.html

Graduate Researcher, Advisor: Prof. Matthew Reynolds

NSF: Center for Sensorimotor Neural Engineering project "Wireless Bidirectional BCI"

University of Washington

Sept. 2014-May 2019

- o Developed 25 Mbps backscatter-based implantable systems using software defined radios, custom RF physical layer communication, and real-time signal processing; demonstrated 25x data-rate improvement compared to prior art. [J1,J2,J3,C2,P2]
- o Designed and implemented wireless, µPower interface for translating the input spectrum of existing neural recording ICs using analog circuit design simulation and fabrication; demonstrated spectral improvement of 19 dB and allowed the reuse of expensive custom ICs. [C1]

Amazon Catalyst Fellow

Amazon Inc.-funded project "Automated Continuous Bladder Irrigation (ACBI)"

University of Washington June 2017-Present

o Developed real-time hardware and firmware for embedded sensor/actuation system to monitor and control the medical procedure of continuous bladder irrigation. The developed device could save \$285 million per year on healthcare in the United States alone. [P1]

Graduate Researcher, Telecom Lab, Advisor: Prof. Aggelos Bletsas

ERC-04-BLASE research project "Backscatter Networks for Large-Scale Environmental Sensing"

Technical University of Crete Dec. 2011-Aug. 2014

o Designed and implemented low-power agricultural/environmental sensor network hardware, firmware, and custom physical layer communication, and signal processing; first demonstration of wireless backscatter sensor network in real-world application. [J4,J5,C5,C6,C7,C8]

Independent Contractor, Supervisor: Prof. Konstantinos Providakis

THALES Programme: "Wireless Admittance Monitoring System (WiAMS)"

Technical University of Crete

Jan. 2011-Jan. 2013

- o Developed a novel wireless real-time monitoring system for structural integrity assessment of concrete structures using piezoelectric sensors; successfully detected cracks in concrete structures in real-time. [J7,J8]
- o Designed and fabricated driving circuit for an admittance measuring system using precision DACs and ADCs. Designed MySQL database with query optimization, UNIX shell scripting and custom driver development for the Raspberry Pi to interface the driving circuit.

Graduate Researcher, Telecom Lab, Advisor: Prof. Aggelos Bletsas

Technical University of Crete

The i-Cubes project: "Remotely Programmable, Low-power, Low-cost WSN from Scratch"

Dec. 2010-Aug. 2011

- o Designed, integrated and fabricated wireless sensor network (WSN) hardware and firmware using 8051 microcontrollers and CC2500 radio ICs; the technology was utilized to build a reliable network for the municipal water company of Chania [J6,C10].
- o Developed firmware with C and 8051 assembly for a custom bootloader that allows over-the-air programming (OTAP) of the WSN; demonstrated OTAP for a network of 5 custom nodes in under 10 seconds. [C9]

Technical skills

TiNA, LTSpice, Cadence

Embedded Systems: 8051, ATMega128, Cortex M0+, Chipcon Radios, Xilinx FPGA/CPLD, VHDL

CAD & Simulation: HFSS, ADS, Eagle Board Design, AutoCAD, Circuit Prototyping/Testing: PCB Milling, RF & SMD Board Fabrication, RF and mixed signal testing

> **Software Tools**: Matlab, C/C++, Java, Gnuradio, Python, Cuda, UNIX Shell scripting, MySQL, CORBA, Java RMI, IDL, Fortran

Leadership

Mentoring: Electronics systems mentor for Amazon Catalyst project (2017-present), IEEE RFID 2017 organizing committee member

Teaching: Teaching and lab assistant for 4 classes (2011-2012), Paid tutor for Matlab, C, Java, Fortran (2010-2014)

Awards/Achievements

Publications: 8 Peer-reviewed Journal publications, 12 Conference publications (IEEE & other), 2 Patents (filed), 3 Theses

Best Paper/Poster: Best Poster, IEEE RFID 2017, Best paper (finalist), IEEE RFID 2017, Top 10% Qualification, IEEE Sensors 2017

Grants: Amazon Catalyst Grant for Project "ACBI", NCESD Grant for Solar Car Project "Hephaestus"

Academic: 3rd Place in health innovation challenge (HIC) in 2017, 1st Prize at the Pan-Hellenic IEEE Final/Diploma Thesis Competition for the years 2009-2011, Graduate Fellowship Award from Technical University of Crete 2011–2013,

Athletic: 2nd Place in the Pan-Cretan Olympic Weightlifting Championship - Preliminary Category 2014.

Patent Applications

[P1]: PCT/US2017/637,311. System and Method for Automated Urine Assessment and Monitoring. Filed 3/1/2018

[P2]: PCT/US2017/016,573. Antenna Elements, Implanted Devices, and Systems for Communication With Implanted Devices. Filed 2/3/2017

Peer-reviewed Journal Publications

[J1]: A. Sharma, E. Kampianakis, J. Rosenthal, A. Pike, A. Dadkhah and M. S. Reynolds, "Wideband UHF DQPSK Backscatter Communication in Reverberant Cavity Animal Cage Environments", IEEE Transactions on Antennas and Propagation, 2019, (early access).

[J2]: E. Kampianakis, A. Sharma, J. Arenas and M. S. Reynolds "A Dual-Band Wireless Power Transfer and Backscatter Communication Approach for Real-Time Neural/EMG Data Acquisition", IEEE Journal of Radio Frequency Identification (JRFID), vol. 1, no. 1, pp. 100-107, March 2017.

[J3]: A. Sharma, E. Kampianakis and M. S. Reynolds. "A dual-band HF and UHF antenna system for implanted neural recording and stimulation devices", in IEEE Antennas and Wireless Propagation Letters, vol. 16, pp. 493-496, 2017.

[J4]: E. Kampianakis, J. Kimionis, K. Tountas, C. Konstantopoulos, E. Koutroulis and A. Bletsas "Wireless Environmental Sensor Networking with Analog Scatter Radio and Timer Principles", in IEEE Sensors Journal, vol. 14, no. 10, pp. 3365-3376, Oct. 2014.

[J5]: S. N. Daskalakis, S. D. Assimonis, E. Kampianakis and A. Bletsas. "Soil moisture Scatter Radio Networking with Low Power", IEEE Trans. on Microwave Theory and Techniques (TMTT), vol. 64, no. 7, pp. 2338-2346, July 2016.

[J6]: A. Bletsas, A. Vlachaki, E. Kampianakis, G. Sklivanitis, J. Kimionis, K. Tountas, M. Asteris, and P. Markopoulos, "Building the low-cost digital garden as a telecom lab exercise", in IEEE Pervasive Computing, vol. 12, no. 1, pp. 48-57, Jan.-Mar. 2013.

[J7]: C. P. Providakis, S. Tsistrakis, M. Voutetaki, Y. Tsompanakis, M. Stavroulaki, J. Agadakos, **E. Kampianakis** and G. Pentes, "A new damage identification approach based on impedance-type measurements and 2D error statistics", Structural Monitoring and Maintenance, vol. 2, no. 4, pp. 319-338, June 2015.

[J8]: C. P. Providakis, E. V. Liarakos, and E. Kampianakis, "Nondestructive Wireless Monitoring of Early-Age Concrete Strength Gain Using an Innovative Electromechanical Impedance Sensing System", Smart Materials Research, 2013.

Selected Peer-reviewed Conference Publications

[C1]: E. Kampianakis and M. S. Reynolds. "A Biosignal Analog Front-End Leveraging Frequency Translation", in proc. IEEE Sensors 2017.

[C2]: E. Kampianakis, A. Sharma, J. Arenas and M. S. Reynolds. "A Dual-Band Wireless Power Transfer and Backscatter Communication Approach for Implantable Neuroprosthetic Devices", in proc. IEEE RFID 2017 Best poster award and best paper nomination.

[C3]: X. Fu, A. Sharma, E. Kampianakis, A. Pedross-Engel, D. Arnitz and M. S. Reynolds. "A Low Cost 10.0-11.1 GHz X-Band Microwave Backscatter Communication Testbed with Integrated Planar Wideband Antennas", in proc. IEEE RFID 2016.

[C4]: J. Rosenthal, E. Kampianakis, A. Sharma, and M. Reynolds, "A 6.25 Mbps, 12.4 pJ/Bit DQPSK Backscatter Wireless Uplink for the NeuroDisc Brain-Computer Interface", in Proc. IEEE Biomedical Circuits and Systems Conference (BioCAS) 2018.

[C5]: S. N. Daskalakis, S. D. Assimonis, E. Kampianakis and A. Bletsas. "Soil Moisture Wireless Sensing with Analog Scatter Radio, Low Power, Ultra-Low Cost and Extended Communication Ranges", in proc. IEEE Sensors, 2014.

[C6]: S. Assimonis, E. Kampianakis and A. Bletsas. "Microwave Analysis and Experimentation for Improved Backscatter Radio", in proc. European Conference on Antennas and Propagation (EuCAP), 2014

[C7]: E. Kampianakis, J. Kimionis, K. Tountas, C. Konstantopoulos, E. Koutroulis and A. Bletsas. "Backscatter Sensor Network for Extended Ranges and Low Cost with Frequency Modulators: Application on Wireless Humidity Sensing", in proc. IEEE SENSORS 2013 Nominated as top %10 among presented papers.

[C8]: C. Konstantopoulos, E. Kampianakis, E. Koutroulis and A. Bletsas. "Wireless Sensor Node for Backscattering Electrical Signals Generated by Plants", in proc. IEEE Sensors 2013

[C9]: E. Kampianakis, J. Kimionis, K. Tountas and A. Bletsas. "A Remotely Programmable Modular Testbed for Backscatter Sensor Network Research", Workshop on Real-World Wireless Sensor Networks (REALWSN) 2013

[C10]: A. Bletsas, A. Vlachaki, E. Kampianakis, G. Sklivanitis, J. Kimionis, K. Tountas, M. Asteris, and P. Markopoulos, "Towards precision agriculture: Building a soil wetness multi-hop WSN from first principles", in proc. 2nd International Workshop in Sensing Technologies in Architecture, Forestry and Environment (ECOSENSE) 2011.